A Guide to the Virginia Intercollegiate Association Papers 1954-1969
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Virginia Intercollegiate Association papers 1954-1969
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
1954-1969
100,000 items.
The records of the Association that governed all non-academic activities of the black high schools in Virginia. This manuscript group has correspondence, photographs, minutes, reports, films,tapes,news clippings and artifacts. The VIA was headquartered at Virginia State University from 1954-1969. Acc #1969-37
Virginia Intercollegiate Association.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
A Tranfer from Virginia State University.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Virginia Interscholastic Association (VIA), which existed from April 1954 through August 1969, was an association of the high schools attended by African-Americans in Virginia. During the years of operation, more than a hundred high schools with a student population of more than forty thousand had membership in the association.
An outgrowth of the Virginia Intersholastic Athletic League (VIAL), which had provided an athletic program for the black schools of the state for several decades, the VIA originated with the Black school principals at the period in Virginia education when the Black high school was developing into a significant part of the school system of the state. Large student enrollments, new school facilities with drama and music departments, gymnasiums and athletic fields, science departments, student newspapers and other organized school activities increased the demand of the students and the community for an adequte program of supervised and organized interschool group relationahip and competitions which would contribute to the fullest development of the high school student.
at the urging of the African-American high school principals Association, Virginia State College requested the general Assembly to appropriate a budget for a central coordinating agency. This agency would administer a state- wide activities program serving the needs of the African-American high school students of the state. Because there was support being provided for the Virginia High School League, A white student activities program administered through the University of Virginia.
In 1954, the General Assembly provided an allocation in the budget of Virginia State College for the administration of a state-wide activities program in the African-Americans high school of the state.
This budget, which was administered by VSTL through the field services division, did not include provision for the operation of the activities which were supported by student membership fees in the high school having membership in the Association. The Legislature support was discontinued in 1969 after the Virginia Interscholastic association was merged with the Virginia High School league as Virginia no longer operated seperate black and white school system.
Scope and Content Information
Minutes, Reports, Correspondence, and Photographs, Printed items and three-dimensional items documenting the programs and activities of the African American secondary schools during the Era of segregation in Virginia. These materials documented how African Americans view the importance of extra curricular activities in the educational matrix?
Series Description
Series I. Minutes and Annual Reports Sub-series A. Executive Committee The Executive committee consists of the minutes from the meetings of this committee there from the years 1954-1969. Some of the topics that were discussed were reclassification of schools, rules and regulations, and the agenda for the legislative council meeting. Also find present is correspondence between the executive committee and various principals of the V.I.A. This section should be helpful in your research.
Sub-series B. The Legislative Committee The Legislative committee was responsible for settling the disputes amongst the V.I.A. The Legislative committee also nominated and voted for the members at large of the executive committee. Also correspondence between the legislative committee and various principals and organizations that were important to the V.I.A. There are a few reports from the executive secretary to the legislative council in 1968-69 the year the VIA came to an end. This file extends from 1954-1969.
Sub-Series C. Annual Reports This series conmsist of annual reports submitted by the executive secretary to the legislative council of the V.I.A. The dates of these reports are from 1955 to 1969. These reports basketball tournaments, the drama and musical festivals and other events throughout the years of the V.I.A. There is also a section where various principals of the VIA correspond with the executive secretary.
Series II. Financial Sub-series A. Budgets This series consist of the proposed budgets of the VIA during the years 1968-1969, salaries invoices from various companies along with inter department requisitions.
Sub-series B. Membership Fees This series consist of the VIA membership fees the years 1958-1961. There are also partial payments papers and the total fees paid by various schols in the VIA.
Sub-series C. Ledgers Reciepts disbursements and deposits according to the bankbook from the year 1953-1955. the second ledger consist of the fees paid by the various high schools and junior high school in the VIA from the years 1954-1966.
Series III. Records Sub-series A. Handbooks These handbooks range in years from 1955 to 1968. These books instruct the V.I.A. members on how each event should be organized. There are also maps, districts, district officers, finances and awards listed in these books.
Sub-series B. Eligibility Records Eligibility records, 1955-1968 were kept inorder to prove who should be allowed to participate in various sporting activities.
Sub-series C. Seasons Records The records of individual schools, games won and lost, district and state championships.
Series IV. Administrative Correspondence Sub-series A. Presidents Office of Virginia State University Correspondence between the executive secretary and the presidents of Virginia State University from 1953- 1969.
Sub-series B. The Executive Secretary's Office Working papers and documents along with memorandums.
Sub-series C. Subject School Correspondence. Correspondence in Memorandums from the presidents office to member schools. Also includes public relations and protest from member schools.
Sub-series D. Member Schools Correspondence. Correspondence by Function.
Series V. Member School Correspondence. Correspondnece between executive secretary and member schools.
Series VI. Photographs Photographs and Printers box documenting the History of the Virginia Interscholastic Association. There are also a few photos from the V.I.A.L.
Series VII. Printed Official programs,flyers Playbills, and Certificates.
Series VIII. Artifacts. Trophies, Medals, and patches used by the VIA
Contents List
- Minutes and Annual Reports
  - The Executive Committee
    - Executive Committee Meetings 1954-1955 (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Executive Committee Correspondence 1954-1955 (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Executive Committee Minutes 1955-1956 (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Executive Committee Correspondence 1955-1956 (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Executive Committee (Budget) 1956-1960 (Box-folder 1:5)
    - Executive Committee Minutes 1956-1957 (Box-folder 1:6)
    - Executive Committee Correspondence 1956-1957 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Executive Committee Minutes 1957-1958 (Box-folder 1:8)
    - Executive Committee Correspondence 1957-1958 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - Executive Committee Minutes 1958-1959 (Box-folder 1:10)
    - Executive Committee V.T.A. Meeting 1959 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - Executive Committee Minutes 1959-1960 (Box-folder 1:12)
    - Executive Committee Correspondence 1959-1960 (Box-folder 1:13)
    - Executive Committee Minutes 1960-1961 (Box-folder 1:14)
    - Executive Committee Correspondence 1960-1961 (Box-folder 1:15)
    - Executive Committee Minutes 1961-1962 (Box-folder 1:16)
    - Executive Committee Correspondence 1961-1962 (Box-folder 1:17)
    - Executive Committee Minutes 1962-1963 (Box-folder 1:18)
    - Executive Committee Correspondence 1962-1963 (Box-folder 1:19)
    - Executive Committee Minutes 1963-1964 (Box-folder 1:20)
    - Executive Committee Correspondence 1963-1964 (Box-folder 1:21)
    - Executive Committee Minutes 1964-1965 (Box-folder 1:22)
    - Executive Committee Correspondence 1964-1965 (Box-folder 1:23)
    - Executive Committee Report 1965 (Box-folder 1:24)
    - Executive Committee Minutes 1965-1966 (Box-folder 2:1)
    - Executive Committee Correspondence 1965-1966 (Box-folder 2:2)
    - Executive Committee Minutes 1966-1967 (Box-folder 2:3)
    - Executive Committee Financial Report 1966-1967 (Box-folder 2:4)
    - Executive Committee Minutes 1967-1968 (Box-folder 2:5)
    - Executive Committee Correspondence 1967-1968 (Box-folder 2:6)
    - Executive Committee Report 1967,1969 (Box-folder 2:7)
    - Executive Committee Minutes 1968-1969 (Box-folder 2:8)
    - Executive Committee Correspondence 1968-1969 (Box-folder 2:9)
    - Executive Committee Report (Box-folder 2:10)
    - Annual report ( Ex. Sec.) 1957 (Box-folder 2:11)
    - Annual Report (Ex. Sec.) 1960-1961 (Box-folder 2:12)
  - The Legislative Council
    - Legislative Council Minutes 1954-1955 (Box-folder 3:1)
    - Legislative Council Correspondence 1954-1955 (Box-folder 3:2)
    - Legislative Council Minutes 1955-1956 (Box-folder 3:3)
    - Legislative Council Correspondence 1955-1956 (Box-folder 3:4)
    - Legislative Council Minutes 1956-1957 (Box-folder 3:5)
    - Legislative Council Correspondence 1956-1957 (Box-folder 3:6)
    - Legislative Council (Report) 1956-1957 (Box-folder 3:7)
    - Legislative Council Minutes 1957-1958 (Box-folder 3:8)
    - Legislative Council Correspondence 1957-1958 (Box-folder 3:9)
    - Legislative Council Minutes 1958-1959 (Box-folder 3:10)
    - Legislative Council Minutes 1959-1960 (Box-folder 3:11)
    - Legislative Council Minutes 1960-1961 (Box-folder 3:12)
    - Legislative Council Minutes 1961-1962 (Box-folder 3:13)
    - Legislative Council Meeting 1961-1962 (Box-folder 3:14)
    - Legislative Council Minutes 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3:15)
    - Legislative Council Correspondence 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3:16)
    - Legislative Council Minutes 1963-1964 (Box-folder 3:17)
    - Legislative Council Minutes 1964-1965 (Box-folder 3:18)
    - Legislative Council Minutes 1965-1966 (Box-folder 3:19)
    - Legislative Council Minutes 1965-1966 (Box-folder 3:20)
    - Legislative Council (Reports) 1967 (Box-folder 3:21)
    - Legislative Council Correspondence 1967-1968 (Box-folder 3:22)
    - Legislative Council (Reports) 1967-1968 (Box-folder 3:23)
    - Legislative Council Minutes 1968-1969 (Box-folder 3:24)
    - Legislative Council (Final Report) 1968-1969 (Box-folder 3:25)
  - Annual Report
    - Membership Fees 1958-1961 (Box-folder 4:1)
    - Membership Fees 1962-1965 (Box-folder 4:2)
    - Deposit Receipts 1968-1969 (Box-folder 4:3)
    - Recommendations for years 1968-1969 (Box-folder 4:4)
    - Annual Report 1954-1955 (Box-folder 4:5)
    - Annual Report 1955-1956 (Box-folder 4:6)
    - Annual Report 1956-1957 (Box-folder 4:7)
    - Annual Report 1958-1959 (Box-folder 4:8)
    - Annual Report 1959-1960 (Box-folder 4:9)
    - Annual Report 1960-1961 (Box-folder 4:10)
    - Annual Report 1962-1963 (Box-folder 4:11)
    - Annual Report 1964-1965 (Box-folder 4:12)
    - The Final Annual Report 1968-1969 (Box-folder 4:13)
    - Financial Reports and Budgets 1953-1955 (Box-folder 4:14)
    - Financial Reports and Budgets 1955-1958 (Box-folder 4:15)
    - Financial Reports and Budgets 1960-1961 (Box-folder 4:16)
    - Financial Reports and Budgets 1962-1963 (Box-folder 4:17)
    - Financial Reports and Budgets 1963-1964 (Box-folder 4:18)
    - Proposed Budget 1964-1966 (Box-folder 4:19)
    - Financial Reports and Budgets 1965-1966 (Box-folder 4:20)
    - Financial Reports and Budgets 1967-1968 (Box-folder 4:21)
    - Budget Activities 1968-1969 (Box-folder 4:22)
- Records
  - Handbooks
    - Ledger Cash Reciepts and Disbuursements 1954-1958 (Box-folder 5:1)
    - Ledger Cash Disbursements 1953-1954 (Box-folder 5:2)
    - Handbooks (Box-folder 5:3)
    - Preliminary Handbooks (2 copies) 1954-1955 (Box-folder 5:4)
    - Handbooks (2 copies) 1957 (Box-folder 5:5)
    - Handbook (2 copies) 1964 (Box-folder 5:6)
    - Handbook 1968 (Box-folder 5:7)
    - Handbook (Student Council) 1958 (Box-folder 5:8)
    - Constitution (Box-folder 5:9)
    - Organization of Student Council in Virginia 1955 (Box-folder 5:10)
    - Directories (Box-folder 5:11)
    - Member Schools (2 copies) 1967-1969 (Box-folder 5:12)
    - History (Box-folder 5:13)
    - History of VIA (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Eligibility Records
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1955 (Box-folder 5A:1)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1956 (Box-folder 5A:2)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1957 (Box-folder 5A:3)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1958 (Box-folder 5A:4)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1958 (Box-folder 5A:5)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1960 (Box-folder 5A:6)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1960 (Box-folder 5A:7)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1962 (Box-folder 5A:8)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1963 (Box-folder 5A:9)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1964 (Box-folder 5A:10)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1964 (Box-folder 5A:11)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1965 (Box-folder 5A:12)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1966 (Box-folder 5A:13)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1966-1967 (Box-folder 5A:14)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1968 (Box-folder 5A:15)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1969 (Box-folder 5A:16)
    - Eligibility List (Baseball) 1969 (Box-folder 5A:17)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1954 (Box-folder 5B:1)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1956 (Box-folder 5B:2)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1957 (Box-folder 5B:3)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1957 (Box-folder 5B:4)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1958 (Box-folder 5B:5)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1959 (Box-folder 5B:6)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1960 (Box-folder 5B:7)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1960 (Box-folder 5B:8)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1961 (Box-folder 5B:9)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1961 (Box-folder 5B:10)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1962 (Box-folder 5B:11)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1964 (Box-folder 5B:12)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1964-1965 (Box-folder 5B:13)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1965 (Box-folder 5B:14)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5B:15)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5B:16)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1967-1968 (Box-folder 5B:17)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1967-1968 (Box-folder 5B:18)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1968-1969 (Box-folder 5B:19)
    - Eligibility List (Basketball) 1968-1969 (Box-folder 5B:20)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1951 (Box-folder 5B:21)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1952 (Box-folder 5B:22)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1953 (Box-folder 5B:23)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1954 (Box-folder 5B:24)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1955 (Box-folder 5B:25)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1955 (Box-folder 5B:26)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1956 (Box-folder 5B:27)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1956 (Box-folder 5B:28)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1957 (Box-folder 5B:29)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1957 (Box-folder 5B:30)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1958 (Box-folder 5B:31)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1959 (Box-folder 5B:32)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1959 (Box-folder 5B:33)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1960 (Box-folder 5B:34)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1960 (Box-folder 5B:35)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1961 (Box-folder 5B:36)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1962 (Box-folder 5B:37)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1962 (Box-folder 5B:38)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1963 (Box-folder 5B:39)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1963 (Box-folder 5B:40)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1963 (Box-folder 5B:41)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1964 (Box-folder 5B:42)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1964 (Box-folder 5B:43)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1965 (Box-folder 5B:44)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1967 (Box-folder 5B:45)
    - Eligibility List (Football) 1968 (Box-folder 5B:46)
  - Season Records
    - District Results central Division Group I 1967 (Box-folder 5C:1)
    - Basketball Results 1963-1964 (Box-folder 5C:2)
    - Eastern Group I 1962, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 5C:3)
    - District Results western Division Group I 1967 (Box-folder 5C:4)
    - District Results, Eastern Division Group I 1967 (Box-folder 5C:5)
    - District Results, Southern Division Group I 1967 (Box-folder 5C:6)
    - Football-Final Standing Group I 1967 (Box-folder 5C:7)
    - Western Division Final Standing 1962-1964,1968 (Box-folder 5C:8)
    - District 5 Results 1961,1962 (Box-folder 5C:9)
    - District 9 Result 1963-1967 (Box-folder 5C:10)
    - Abramas, S.C. High School 1955-1962 (Box-folder 5C:11)
    - Addison, Lucy High School 1960-1965 (Box-folder 5C:12)
    - Armstrong (Richmond) High School 1955, 1965 (Box-folder 5C:13)
    - Bethume, Mary M. High School 1961-1965 (Box-folder 5C:14)
    - Brookvale High School 1960, 1962, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 5C:15)
    - Bruton Heights High School 1955 (Box-folder 5C:16)
    - Bunche, Ralph High School 1955-1956 (Box-folder 5C:17)
    - Burley, jackson P. High School 1961-1965 (Box-folder 5C:18)
    - Campbell, County High School 1965,1968 (Box-folder 5C:19)
    - Carver, George Washington High School 1954-1969 (Box-folder 5C:20)
    - Carver, George Washington High School 1961-1966 (Box-folder 5C:21)
    - Carver, George Washington High School 1960 (Box-folder 5C:22)
    - Carver, George Washington High School 1955, 1958 (Box-folder 5C:23)
    - Carver, George Washington High School 1962-1965 (Box-folder 5C:24)
    - Carver, George Washington High School 1956,1959-1961,1965 (Box-folder 5C:25)
    - Carver, George Washington High School 1964-1967 (Box-folder 5C:26)
    - Carver, George Washington High School 1961,1967 (Box-folder 5C:27)
    - Central High School 1955-1956,1961,1965 (Box-folder 5C:28)
    - Central High School 1958 (Box-folder 5C:29)
    - Central High School 1957 (Box-folder 5C:30)
    - Central High School 1959-1963 (Box-folder 5C:31)
    - Crestwood High School 1955-1965 (Box-folder 5C:32)
    - Criser High School 1959-1960 (Box-folder 5C:33)
    - Dean, Jennie High School 1964-1965 (Box-folder 5C:34)
    - Dunbar High School 1955-1965 (Box-folder 5C:35)
    - Douglas High School 1954-1967 (Box-folder 5C:36)
    - East End High School 1954-1969 (Box-folder 5C:37)
    - St. Emma Military Academy 1954-1969 (Box-folder 5C:38)
    - Essex County High School 1954-1969 (Box-folder 5C:39)
    - Foster, Luther high School 1955,1969 (Box-folder 5C:40)
    - Gandy, John M High School 1955, 1968 (Box-folder 5C:41)
    - Gibson, Susie G High School 1965, 1968 (Box-folder 5C:42)
    - Goochland, Central High School 1955 (Box-folder 5C:43)
    - Russell Grove High school 1954-1969 (Box-folder 5C:44)
    - Hayden High School 1954-1969 (Box-folder 5C:45)
    - Parker-Gray High School 1955-1967 (Box-folder 5C:46)
    - Walker-Grant High School 1955-1967 (Box-folder 5C:47)
    - Franklin County High School 1954-1955 (Box-folder 5C:48)
    - Harris Albert High School 1955, 1965 (Box-folder 5C:49)
    - Hamilton Holmes High School 1955 (Box-folder 5C:50)
    - Halifax County High School 1955 (Box-folder 5C:51)
    - Heights, Burton High School 1955,1965 (Box-folder 5C:52)
    - Hunter, Thomas High School 1955 (Box-folder 5C:53)
    - Huntington High School 1955, 1966 (Box-folder 5C:54)
    - I.C. Norcom High School 1957, 1965 (Box-folder 5C:55)
    - Jackson, Luther P. High School 1954, 1966 (Box-folder 5C:56)
    - Jackson, Luther P. High School 1955, 1969 (Box-folder 5C:57)
    - Jefferson High School 1955,1957 (Box-folder 5C:58)
    - Johnson, A.T. High School (Box-folder 5C:59)
    - Johnson, james weldon High School 1955, 1964 (Box-folder 5C:60)
    - Kennedy, John 1954-1969 (Box-folder 5D:1)
    - Langston, John M. 1954, 1969 (Box-folder 5D:2)
    - Lunenburg H. School 1954, 1969 (Box-folder 5D:3)
    - Moore, J. E. J. 1955, 1966 (Box-folder 5D:4)
    - Sussex County Training School 1954, 1969 (Box-folder 5D:5)
    - Taylor, Williams C 1954-1969 (Box-folder 5D:6)
    - Tazewell County High School 1955,1963 (Box-folder 5D:7)
    - Tyler, George High School 1954,1969 (Box-folder 5D:8)
    - Union High School 1954,1969 (Box-folder 5D:9)
    - Union High School 1964,1966 (Box-folder 5D:10)
    - Walker, Maggie High School 1954, 1969 (Box-folder 5D:11)
    - Walker, St. Claire High School 1954-1969 (Box-folder 5D:12)
    - Walker, Thomas High School 1956,1968 (Box-folder 5D:13)
    - Washington, Booker T. High School 1954-1969 (Box-folder 5D:14)
    - Washington, Booker T. High School 1954-1969 (Box-folder 5D:15)
    - Washington, Booker T. High School 1954-1969 (Box-folder 5D:16)
    - Washington, Booker T. High School 1954-1969 (Box-folder 5D:17)
    - Watson High School 1955, 1965 (Box-folder 5D:18)
    - West End High School 1954,1969 (Box-folder 5D:19)
    - Westside High School 1962,1969 (Box-folder 5D:20)
    - Wight, Isle of Training School 1954, 1969 (Box-folder 5D:21)
    - Woodson, Carter G. High School 1954,1969 (Box-folder 5D:22)
    - Woodson, carter G. High School 1954,1969 (Box-folder 5D:23)
    - Wright, A. T. High School 1954, 1969 (Box-folder 5D:24)
    - Wyatt, Edward W High School 1954, 1969 (Box-folder 5D:25)
- Administrative Correspondence
  - Presidents office Virginia State University
    - Daniel Robert P 1953-1958 (Box-folder 6:1)
    - Daniel Robert P 1959-1960 (Box-folder 6:2)
    - Daniel Robert P 1961-1962 (Box-folder 6:3)
    - Daniel Robert P 1963-1964 (Box-folder 6:4)
    - Quarles, Walker 1967-1969 (Box-folder 6:5)
    - Tucker, James 1968-1969 (Box-folder 6:6)
  - The Executive Secretary's Office
    - Paige, C.D. 1954-1955 (Box-folder 6:7)
    - Paige (Planning) 1954-1957 (Box-folder 6:8)
    - Paige (Planning) 1958-1959 (Box-folder 6:9)
    - Paige (Planning) 1960 (Box-folder 6:10)
    - Paige (Planning) 1961 (Box-folder 6:11)
    - Paige (Planning) 1962 (Box-folder 6:12)
    - Paige (Planning) 1963 (Box-folder 6:13)
    - Paige (Planning) 1964 (Box-folder 6:14)
    - Paige (Planning) 1965- January/June (Box-folder 6:15)
    - Paige, C.D. 1954-1955 (Box-folder 7:1)
    - Womble, Charles 1965 - July/December (Box-folder 7:2)
    - Womble, Charles 1965 November/December (Box-folder 7:3)
    - Womble, Charles (Planning Committee) 1965 October/November (Box-folder 7:4)
    - Womble, Charles 1969 (Box-folder 7:5)
    - Womble, Charles 1967 Jan/June (Box-folder 7:6)
    - Womble, Charles 1967 July/December (Box-folder 7:7)
    - Womble, Charles 1968 July/December (Box-folder 7:8)
    - Womble, Charles 1969 (Box-folder 7:9)
    - Virginia High School League- Merger Talks 1967-1969 (Box-folder 7:10)
    - Virginia High School League- Committee Meeting 1967-1969 (Box-folder 7:11)
    - VIA- Honoraria 1966-1967 (Box-folder 7:12)
    - VIA- Memorandum 1954 (Box-folder 7:13)
    - VIA- Memorandum 1955 - January/June (Box-folder 7:14)
    - VIA Memorandum 1955 July/December (Box-folder 7:15)
    - Miscellanous 1965 (Box-folder 7:16)
    - Miscellaneous 1966 (Box-folder 7:17)
  - Subject Schools Correspondence
    - Member School Correspondence 1957-1965 (Box-folder 8:1)